

7575 Hollandale Drive Colorado Springs, CO 80919 719.321.8131 kaseyleigh1978@gmail.com

Portfolio link:

KcRaymond.github.io/portfolio/

# **Objective**

To obtain a creative/art director position where I can present and implement my wide spectrum of hands on design experience. Also to secure a fulfilling opportunity to create stunning visual communication materials and campaigns to take a companies branding to the next level of their goals. My natural talents, on point attention to details and 20+ years of visual communication experience are invaluable skills that I will bring full force.

## **Education**

## **Collins College**

Phoenix, Arizona

Bachelor's Degree in Visual Communications / Marketing

Emphasis: Graphic Design, Illustration/Rendering, Web Design and Print Production, Apple Computer Technology

- Student of the Month (August 1997)
- GPA 3.85, Graduated with Honors

## Work Experience

### Art Director / Web Designer and Developer / SEO Specialist

2016 - 2020

Slavens Racing - Colorado Springs, Colorado

- Complete design and art direction across all facets: website, email marketing, video design/editing, ads, apparel
- Manage, update and redesign of large ecommerce website: www.slavensracing.com
- Setup and implemented international shipping calculator, fitment finder, wholesale dealer website
- Added more functionality (wishlists and inventory tracking) and doubled the size of the products and content
- SEO specialist generated more traffic to the website after a large scale SEO strategy
- Trained and managed website support employees in web design, maintenance and best practices

## **Art Director / Marketing and Event Assistant**

2003 - 2008

Display Image Trade Show Marketing - Colorado Springs, Colorado

- Complete design process and final production of marketing collateral for a wide spectrum of clients (specializing in trade show displays and all related mailers, ads, brochures, magazines, giveaways, etc.)
- Design of large format banners, back-lit displays, corporate interiors and billboards
- Create graphic layouts for marketing and budgeting presentations to clients, including PowerPoint/video presentations
- Direct and manage freelance artists and ensure deadlines are met in a multi-project schedule
- Final proofing and quality check of all digital files handed off from freelance artists
- Direct and manage freelance photographers at client photo shoots
- Support event exhibitors in their video presentation setup and operations
- Coordinate all printing with many different suppliers to meet deadlines: CMYK offset and digital preparation
- Maintain all Mac/Apple computers, printers, networking and hardware/software problems
- Attend trade shows and assist in the budgeting, production, and marketing of the various expos
- Responsible for all purchase orders to suppliers and paper work/quotes for clients files

#### Senior Graphic Artist / Packaging Technician / Marketing Support

2000 - 2003

Western Forge / Subdivision of Emerson Electric Co. - Colorado Springs, Colorado

- Complete design from concept to final production of tool packaging for Sears (Craftsman ®) and Home Depot (Ridgid®, Husky®) branded tools
- Work with marketing department to create graphic intense presentations for clients
- Technical writing and editing on all tool packaging
- Color proofing all packaging and color correction when needed, Prep and send all artwork to printers
- Design of POP displays and store signage for clients
- Mock up new tool designs in Photoshop and Illustrator

continued...

- Design intranet website for Emerson Tool Company Divison
- Edit and proof all Spanish on bilingual packaging
- Extensive work with dielines, Pantone color and CMYK process printing

## Senior Graphic Artist 1999 — 2000

Rocky Mountain Motorworks - Woodland Park, Colorado

- Layout and design of three biyearly magazines (air cooled VW, water cooled VW, BMW)
- · Manage production artists and keep on schedule for deadlines
- · Work with in-house photographer on cover shots and product shots
- · Conceptualize, design and submit monthly magazine ads
- Image preparation for web site and banner ads, including color correction of catalog photography for CMYK
- Collect all catalogs for printing output and handle quotes from printers
- · Responsible for catalog blue line proofing

#### **Graphic Artist / Media Coordinator**

1998 - 1999

2005, 2006

1999

1996

1996

1994

1993

Leading Edge Air Foils, Inc. / Raisner Aircraft Depot, Inc. - Meadowlake Airport, Peyton, Colorado

- Responsible for maintaining a 350 page catalog and 100 page supplemental published yearly
- · Design and submit newspaper and magazine ads monthly
- Construct displays and design promotional, informational flyers for trade shows
- Write and distribute company press releases
- · Provide photography and prepare images and PDF files for all collateral
- Draw technical illustrations and engine diagrams

## **Related Skills**

- Ninja like computer skills with advanced knowledge of professional design programs including: WordPress,
   Apple iMovie & Adobe video software, InDesign, Illustrator, Photoshop, Word, PowerPoint
- · Can work cross-platform on both Mac and PC computers to achieve the highest degree of flexibility
- Knowledge of Mac OS X operating systems, networking, troubleshooting and repair
- Excellent color correction skills and photo manipulation in Photoshop
- · Color separations for screen printing and embroidery digitizing
- · Talented illustrator and mural painter
- · Excellent multi-tasker and can handle tight deadlines

Display Image, Best of Show, trade show display design

Air Academy Federal Credit Union Art Scholarship, 3rd place

Air Academy Federal Credit Union Art Scholarship, 3rd place

Pikes Peak League Art Show - Advanced, 2nd place

Pikes Peak Community College Art Show, 1st place

· Currently earning a certificate in Full Stack Web Development from Denver University

Leading Edge Air Foils, Best Rotax Air Show Internet and Print Advertising Support

## **Freelance**

1 100101100	
Out West Awning Co.  • Setup, manage, and maintain the graphics department including: large format princutters, SGS machine. Create customer renderings, design all print pieces and w	
<ul><li>The Edge Screen Printing</li><li>T-shirt design, color separations for screens, and embroidery digitizing</li></ul>	2004 — 2013
<ul> <li>KLR Designs</li> <li>Various design jobs, website design, hat textile design (styling, dying, production)</li> <li>Mural painting (commercial &amp; residential), contract work for local ad agencies</li> </ul>	<b>2002 — 2020</b> ),
<ul> <li>Amark Budget Sign</li> <li>Design signs, banners, decals, logos, flyers, and www.Abudgetsigns.com</li> <li>Train other designers in Photoshop, Illustrator, and large format design/printing</li> <li>Prepare files for vinyl cutter and Mimaki large format printer</li> </ul>	2007 — 2013
Honors and Awards	